Abdoulkader Abdourhamane Haidara

Moskovskoye Shosse, 25, Dolgoprudny, Moskovskaya oblast (Moscow).

+7 (925) 560-47-69

<u>abdoulkaderhaidaramali@gmail.com</u> khaidara.a@phystech.edu

Github: <a>@teyalite

ABOUT

Well qualified software developer familiar with a wide range of programming languages and utilities.

Solid knowledge in mathematics and worked with most of the popular data structures and implemented well known algorithms.

Knowledgeable of backend and frontend developments requirements. Collaborative teammate with easy team integration and excellent team working abilities.

EXPERIENCE

HackBio, Remote — *Software Developer*

December 2021 - Present

Build and maintain all HackBio's applications.

I work principally with **Typescript/Javascript** for both backend and frontend and use the following frameworks and libraries: **Reactjs**, **Nextjs**, **Nestjs**, **Mui** etc.

PostgreSQL is used as a database.

Freelance, Remote — *Software Developer*

October 2020 - Present

I worked with some people & organizations on their projects.

- Studappy
- Open Russie

EDUCATION

Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology, Moscow — Bachelor in Computer Science

September 2020 - Present

Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms(C++), Programming Languages (C++, Java, Python), Calculus, Geometry, Linear algebra, Number Theory and Number System, Mathematical Thinking, Discrete Mathematics, Research Practice,

SKILLS

Data structures & Algorithms. Programming Languages:

- C/C++
- Java
- Typescript/Javascript
- SQL
- Python
- HTML/CSS
- Go.

Technologies/Environment:

- ML Tools
- Linux & MacOs
- Node.js
- PostgreSQL
- MySQL & MariaDB
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Git
- FASTApi
- React & React Native
- Flutter
- Spring Boot
- MongoDB

AWARDS & HONORS

- Russian Government Scholarship 2019 - Present

LANGUAGES

English, French, Russian

Combinatorics and Graphs, **Graph Theory**, Complex Networks(Networkx), **Operating Systems**, Databases, **Probability Theory**, Differential Equations, Constraint Programming, **Machine Learning**, Parallel and Distributed Computing, **Convex Optimization**, Russian as a Foreign Language.

National Research University Higher School of Economics, Moscow — Preparatory Course

October 2019 - July 2020

Coursework: Russian as a Foreign Language, Physics, Mathematics, Programming in C.

PROJECTS

Real time chat application for desktop — Using Qt in C++ — (View on Github)

Client-server model based real time chat application for desktop, allowing local network connection as well as connection through the internet. TCP/IP protocol is used to send messages.

Client-server multithreading downloader in — Using the Go programming language and Javascript — (<u>View on Github</u>)

The downloader makes use of RFC7233 to identify the size of the resource to download, and then initiates partial downloads concurrently with the help of multiple go-routines, once all segments are downloaded, we finally merge all the individual segments into the final file.

Reddit Clone Api — *Using Python, FASTApi & Docker & Kubernetes* — (<u>View on Github</u>)

Part of a student software development project.